( HANNAH SINGING MELANCHOLY TUNE )
) ( COMPUTER CHIMES
( TYPING )
Oh . ( INHALES SHARPLY )
( GROANING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( EXHALES )
Son of a bitch !
( MELANCHOLY TUNE PLAYING )
LOCKHART : No , we can 't touch the munis .
al We 'll use them as collater
. for a leveraged equity position in Cisco
Then I want you to take everything out of
First National and move it over to Banyon .
J , you mean Delaware ? I thought that was dead .
That 's resurrected .
We need to clean up the Reynolds account ...
in case those fucks at AML decide to do their job .
Are you sure about this ?
. Nothing on email
Move everything ba ck on Monday .
? You paying attention
( STAMMERS ) Yeah , yeah , I am .
Tickets ? I don 't know if ...
I 'm sending the numbers through now .
What about Green ?
t . Uh , stall him . I don 't give a shi
o . Call in sick if you have t
Business or pleasure ?
. I don 't know . I just ..
Seriously ?
Look , I don 't know if I feel comfortable ...
y . Josh ! Josh ! Stop being such a puss
Just do what I tell you to do , and call me when it 's done .
( SIGHS )
PEMBROKE : To my fellow members of the board .
A man cannot unsee the truth .
He cannot willingly return to darkness ...
or go blind once he has the gift of sight ...
any more than he can be unborn .
We are the only species capable of self-reflection .
The only species with the toxin of self-doubt
written into our genetic code .
Unequal to our gifts , we build ,
we buy , we consume .
We wrap ourselves in the illusion
of material success .
We cheat and deceive as we claw our way ...
to the pinnacle of what we define as achievement .
Superiority to other men .
JOSH : ( WHISTLES ) Corner office .
Who 'd you have to blow ?
I heard he closed the Reynolds account .
How exactly did you do that ?
s . Just that good , I gues
Don 't forget about us little people .
I ? Oh , how could
You know how I take my coffee .
Excuse me , but they wanna see you upstairs
in the partners boardroom .
Tell them I 'll be right there .
Oh , and tomorrow is your mother 's birthday .
Get her something for me , would you ?
Of course .
PEMBROKE : There is a sickness inside us .
Rising like the bile that leaves
that bitter taste at the back of our throats .
It 's there in every one of you seated around the table .
We deny its existence until one day
the body rebels against the mind ...
and screams out ,
" I am not a well man . " ( YAWNS )
No doubt you will think only of the merger .
That unclean melding of two equally diseased institutions .
But the truth cannot be ignored .
For only when we know what ails us
can we hope to find the cure .
I will not return .
Do not attempt to contact me again .
Sincerely , Roland E. Pembroke .
GREEN : Well , Mr. Lockhart ...
what do you make of that ?
Clearly , he 's lost his mind .
. Our thoughts exactly
n , Man goes for a two-week spa vacatio
and has a complete mental breakdown .
Who the hell takes the waters in the 21st century anyway ?
I trust you understand the sensitivity
of some of the information in that letter .
So it 's true .
GREEN : A merger of this kind will make us ...
one of the biggest financial service firms
d . on the Eastern Seaboar
Something that stands to enrich everyone in this room .
WILSON : Including you .
We hear good things .
Your work on the Reynold s account was inspired .
WILSON : Of course , the SEC will want
unfettered acces s to our books .
. Any irregularities are sure to come out
You didn 't really think we wouldn 't find out ?
I don 't know what you 're talking about .
You think there 's a trick you can pull we haven 't tried ?
r . This is amateu
Can I ask you somethin g , Mr. Lockhart ?
You ever have a 12-inch black dick in your ass ?
Prison , Mr. Lockhart .
. HOLLIS : You 're i n a lot of trouble
If that were the case ,
you would have already turned me in .
So , my guess is the SEC
is after someone a little more senior .
Someone on the board , perhaps .
Or someone who 's clearly unstable .
nd We 'd like you to go to Switzerla
and bring Mr. Pembroke back to us .
You see ...
gh the merger cannot go throu
without Mr. Pembroke signing off ...
I don 't have the rel
with Mr. Pembroke that Morris had .
s . Fuck Morri
GREEN : Now , Morris was a good salesman ,
dependable family man .
God rest his soul .
But he didn 't have vision .
Someone has to take responsibility .
( INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT OVER PA )
LOCKHART : Josh , it 's me again .
In an hour and a half , the Nikkei closes .
When it does , I want you to empty Banyon
and buy puts in Glenco .
I 'm sending the details over now .
And fucking call me back .
I don 't like leaving messages like this .
( TYPING )
You 're here for the cure ?
No , I 'm just visiting .
You mind ?
Go ahead .
You 're younger than most of my passengers .
Do a lot of driving for the sanitarium ?
All the driving .
Every week , I pick up rich people from the train ...
and take them up the mountain .
Only rich people , huh ?
Must be expensive .
Well , wealthy people have wealthy problems .
Me , I 'm happy with a simple life .
That 's it ? No ambition ?
Just drive people up and down the mountain ?
Most people tend to stay .
Most peoplWhy 's that ? tay .
I guess they like it there .
. Oh , shit
I don 't go in for spas and that kind of thing .
I work for a living , like my father before me .
A son learns what it is to be a man from his father .
Am I right ?
w . I wouldn 't kno
. I didn 't grow up with my father
LOCKHART 'S MOTHER : How long will you be gone ?
LOCKHART : Just a few days . It 's business .
( MUZAK PLAYING )
LOCKHART 'S MOTHER : You don 't look well .
I 'm fine . I just haven 't been sleeping much .
. You need to rest
You know , I always told your father to rest ...
but he wouldn 't listen .
He was weak .
m . You didn 't know hi
And whose fault is that ?
So , are you happy here ?
Are they taking good care of you ?
People come here to di e . Why would I be happy ?
I 'm getting a promotion .
So , when I get back
I 'll be able to move you to somewhere better .
Somewhere near the beach or something .
You won 't come back .
Of course I will .
Another ballerina ?
She 's not like the others .
Why 's that ?
. She lives in a dream
( MELANCHOLY TUNE PLAYING ON MUSIC BOX )
But she 's dancing .
That 's because she doesn 't know she 's dreaming .
( HORN BLARING )
( ENRICO EXCLAIMS IN GERMAN )
( SPEAKING GERMAN ) ( ENRICO SHOUTING IN GERMAN )
Friendly bunch .
Yeah .
There 's always been bad blood
between the villagers and the people on the hill .
Why 's that ?
y . ENRICO : Histor
How old is this place ?
Foundations date back to the time of the barons .
For centuries , all this la nd and everyone in it ...
belonged to one family .
The Von Reichmerls .
What happened to them ?
Hmm . Interesting story .
Apparently , the last baron
was so obsessed with the purity of his bloodline ...
he decided only his sister
was clean enough to carry his child .
d . When the church forbade the union , he renounced Go
That must have gone over well .
t . No shi
So on his wedding night ...
the villagers came up the hill ...
chased the Baron and his bride into the catacombs ...
and made him watch while they burned her alive .
Then they burned the whole place to the ground .
That 's a hell of a story .
Yeah .
But that was 200 years ago .
A lot 's changed since then .
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
20 minutes max .
. No hurry
Welcome !
May I help you ?
I 'm here to see a guest . Mr. Roland Pembroke .
I 'm sorry , but visiting hour s are over for the day .
( CHUCKLES )
. I 've come a long way
Maybe you could make an exception .
s . There are no exception
Is there a manager I could speak to ?
Sign here .
Please .
t . Thank you , Mr. Lockhar
I 'll see what I can do .
NAIR : You won 't get any service here .
Part of the treatment .
You get used to it .
What 's a ten-letter word for amnesty ?
a . No ide
Exemption .
Nope . That 's only nine .
Absolution .
Yes !
You like puzzles ?
Not really .
MAN : You mind ?
Thank you .
I believe the reception nurse explained ...
that visiting hours end at 3 : 00 p.m. precisely .
She did . But as I 'm su re you 're aware ...
EO Mr. Pembroke remains the C
of a major financi al institution .
s , Under the circumstance
I was hoping you can make an ...
exception .
Vitamins .
If we are to help the peop le that come here ...
. we must keep up our strength
May one ask what it is concerning ?
It 's a business matter .
I 'm not at liberty to sa y any more than that .
Of course . And I hope you understand
s . that we also have our rule
Our treatments here are most effective ...
when exposure to the stresses
of the modern world is strictly limited .
Director Volmer is quite firm on that .
LOCKHART : Hydrotherapy ?
That is correct .
That 's a long way to com e just for water .
The sanitarium is built over an ancient aquifer ...
that offers uniquely rejuvenating qualities .
LOCKHART : Rebuilt .
After the fire .
Yes .
History is full of darkness .
If you would like to leave a note ...
I 'd happily pass it along to Mr. Pembroke .
Mr. Pieterson ?
I understand the work you do here is important ...
and you 're obviously a very busy man .
But if you wouldn 't mind finding time between
administering aqua aerobics and Jacuzzis ...
to inform Mr. Pembroke he has a visitor ...
with information of the utmost urgency to him personally ...
I 'd be grateful .
On the other hand , if you want me to write a note ...
so you can slip it under his door
with his breakfast tray ...
on the off-chance he notices it
before his morning rubdown ...
I 'm afraid that 's not gonna cut it .
You see , I just traveled 4,000 miles to get here .
There 's a red-eye going back to New York tonight ...
and I intend Mr. Pembroke and I to be on it .
( FAUCET DRIPPING )
You plan to take Mr. Pembrok e back to New York with you ?
Is that a problem ?
Of course , it is entirel y up to Mr. Pembroke .
. He 's a patient , not a prisoner
He 'll be in treatmen t until after 7 : 00 .
If you 'd like to come back then ,
I 'll make sure he 's available .
Thank you for your understanding .
NAIR : Leaving already ?
WATKINS : What a nice-looking young man .
Where 's your friend ?
What time 's the last train to Zurich ?
Not till 10 : 00 .
Get me to a hotel . I gotta make a call .
( HANNAH SINGING MELANCHOLY TUNE )
Pretty girl .
( BOTH SHOUT )
( SCREECHING ) ( TIRES SCREECHING )
What the fuck !
( GASPS )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( MELANCHOLY TUNE PLAYING ON MUSIC BOX )
LOCKHART 'S MOTHER : How long will you be gone ?
LOCKHART : Just a few days .
Are we waiting for someone else ?
. There is no one else
( WHIMPERING )
Sleep well ?
Uh ...
r . I can 't remember having slept bette
VOLMER : It 's the mountain air .
Mr. Lockhart ...
my name is Henrich Volmer .
I am the director of the sanitarium here .
How long have I been here ?
Three days .
Oh , Jesus !
You can count yourself lucky . It was a clean break .
Although I do feel partly responsible .
The locals tell me
I should hunt the deer on the property ...
but I can 't bring myself
to harm the innocent creatures .
After all , they were here long before us .
I need to call New York .
I took the liberty of informing your office
of the accident , if that 's your concern .
They agreed with me ...
that business can wait and your health cannot .
? Hank Green said that
Even the acting head
of a major Wall Street finance firm ...
can 't argue with the consequences
of a serious car accident .
We don 't get many visitors here .
Most of my patients have done extraordinary things .
Built vast fortunes ...
commanded great empires ...
but at a terrible cost .
They have no one who cares for them .
Mr. Pembroke is lucky .
He has you .
So , do your best to relax .
Enjoy yourself .
You are at the foot of the Swiss Alps ...
one of the most beautiful places in the world .
Think of it as an enforced vacation .
Although I know you Americans
are not so good at vacations , are you ?
And remember , you 're at altitude .
It can take a while to acclimatize ...
so please make sure you drink plter .
. Believe me , you 're in good hands
( WATCH TICKING )
( TICKING STOPS )
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
Are you lost ?
Uh ... Yeah .
. I guess so
Where is it you 're supposed to be ?
I don 't know .
Name ?
Pembroke .
Roland Pembroke .
Here it is .
Pembroke . Room 609 . Steam bath .
( CHUCKLES )
Of course .
Mr. Pembroke ...
the steam baths are in that direction .
ATTENDANT : You can 't go in there .
Not like that .
Pembroke ?
? It is Mr. Pembroke , isn 't it
Do I know you ?
My name is Lockhar t . Mr. Green sent me .
. I thought they 'd send Morris
. Morris is dead
Heart attack .
Mr. Pembroke , I 've come to bring you back to New York .
You want me to leave here ?
s . Just for a few day
I 'm afraid I can 't do that .
Why not ?
I 'm not well .
. You look all right to me
That 's because you are blind .
As I was .
But soon you 'll see .
Rest assured , they 'll take good care of you here .
I 'm not a patient .
What happened to your leg ?
k Mr. Pembroke , the situation in New Yor
s . is really quite seriou
No longer my concern .
The director says I must not involve myself
in business matters .
? Have you met Director Volmer
This morning .
He is a great man .
Kind man .
Not like other doctors .
. Mr. Pembroke ..
This obsession with blood .
You see , they have it all wrong .
Do you know the body is 65 % water ?
It 's our fluids that must led .
. Word that the merger is in trouble has leaked
I . The share pric e is in free fal
Lockhart ?
You 're not any relation to Henry Lockhart , are you ?
My father .
You knew him ?
We started out together .
Terrible , what happened to him .
They said there was a boy left in the car .
I don 't remember much , to be honest .
He didn 't deserve what we did to him .
What do you mean ?
He was an honest man .
And we destroyed him for it .
Well , people get fucked ov er every day .
Either you have what it take s to survive , or you don 't .
And I suppose you do .
Is that why you came all this way ?
Ambition ?
Then you have it worse than any of us .
What 's that ?
The sickness .
Your father saw the truth long before the rest of us .
The pointlessness of the entire endeavor .
We 've all done terrible things .
So many terrible things .
What 's it trading at ?
What ?
The stock ! What 's it trading at ?
Eight and a half at close on Friday .
Parasites .
It 'll be lower by now .
We 're all concerned for yo ur well-being , Mr. Pembroke .
Mmm .
Just a few days .
There are certai n irregularities
in some of the accounts ...
that need to be clarified before
d . the merger can be complete
And I suppose someone has to take responsibility .
t . Something like tha
Then I better get my things .
I need a car to take me to the station .
Will you call one for me , please ?
I 'll see what I can do .
( PEOPLE CHATTERING )
That 's where the baron hung the priest .
What 's that ? See ?
The church would have been right over there ...
where that funny little building is now .
I 'm sure of it .
People used to come from miles around ...
for the miracles attributed to the holy water .
Guess some thing s don 't change .
How marvelous .
Terrible thing , though . Such violence .
. That 's what you get for marrying your sister
Sister ?
t ? Yeah , it was all about a pure bloodline , wasn 't i
How fascinating !
I must look into that .
! HILL : Glad to see you 're back on your feet
We heard about the accident .
You 're American , aren 't you , Mister ...
. Lockhart
Frank Hill . Stockholm .
And this is Mr. Nair from London .
Bombay , originally .
I see you 've met Mrs. Watkins , our amateur historian .
Yes , of course . How rude .
Victoria Watkins . 40 years at Xerox .
NAIR : Why don 't you pull up a chair ?
We need a fourth .
Careful . Like most Brahmins , he cheats .
, Coming from a venture capitalist
t . I take that as a complimen
Actually , I was just on my way back
to New York with Mr. Pembroke .
Then he 's ...
He 's feeling better ?
Well enough .
I suppose that 's wonderful news .
Isn 't that right , Mr. Nair ?
. NAIR : Wonderful news
ATTENDANT : Mrs. Watkins ...
time for your treatment .
Yes , of course .
Pleasure to meet you , Mr. Lockhart .
Safe travels .
( HANNAH SINGING MELANCHOLY TUNE )
( CONTINUES SINGING )
Something in the water ?
At the bottom .
. I don 't see anything
Did it hurt ?
. Can 't remember
Better that way .
( RESUMES SINGING ) I saw you .
Before .
Are you a patient here ?
It 's just , you 're so much younger
than everyone else .
. Director Volmer sa ys I 'm a special case
? What about you
Are you here for the cure ?
No . ( CHUCKLES )
. Actually , I was just leaving
No one ever leaves .
What are you talking about ?
? Why would anyone want to
Yeah , I see your point . ( RESUMES SINGING )
Did you get what you came for ?
. Well , I came to bring someone back to New York
d . So , yeah . I di
Does he want to go ?
Not really .
That song you were singing .
? Where did you learn that
I have to go now .
What 's your name ?
Hannah .
( DINGING INSISTENTLY )
Mr. Pembroke ?
Where 's Pembroke ?
The patient that was in this room , where is he ?
I thought you were Pembroke .
) ( CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
VOLMER : Do you know what they used to recommend
for the common stomach ailment ?
The application of leeches .
Based on the diagnosis , I always pitied the leech .
( ALL LAUGHING )
Mmm . Mr. Lockhart ...
please , won 't you join us ?
The sturgeon is excellent ,
unless of course you prefer the venison .
I couldn 't let it go to waste .
Where 's Pembroke ?
Mr. Pembroke has unfortunately taken a turn for the worse .
. I fear your conversation about business matters ..
has set him back somewhat .
But , no matter . We have moved him on
to the next stage of treatment .
He looked all right to me .
But you 're not a doctor .
Maybe it 's time for a second opinion .
VOLMER : That , of course , is up to Mr. Pembroke .
And he 's not available .
Ever since I got here ...
you people have been giving me the runaround .
I would ask you please to keep your voice down .
We wouldn 't wanna upset the clientele , would we ?
VOLMER : Mr. Lockhart , giving you the runaround
is the furthest thing from my mind .
My sole concern is for the welfare of my patients .
r . It 's bad for business if people start getting bette
Am I right ?
What are you implying , Mr. Lockhart ?
Old people paying through the teeth for what ? Water ?
y ? What 's your overhead anywa
. That is not your concern
I don 't wanna have to get lawyers involved ...
but I came to get Pembroke back to New York ...
, and that 's what I 'm gonna do
if I have to hit h im over his head ...
and drag him out by his hair .
e . Are you feeling all right , Mr. Lockhart ? You seem pal
I 'm fine .
You 're bleeding .
What ?
( GROANS SOFTLY )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Perhaps you should sit down .
VOLMER : No signs of concussion .
Any headaches , hallucinations ?
No .
You may dress .
Are you drinking the water ?
( SIGHS ) Yes .
Good .
Make sure you do .
I took the liberty of running a few tests
after the accident .
Hannah .
? Isn 't it
Yes .
She 's a very special case .
y ? What does that mean exactl
She was exposed to serious trauma
when she was very young .
Her development was delayed .
Hannah did not utter a word until she was 11 years old .
Please understand ...
Mr. Lockhart ...
she is like a daughter to me .
But we 're here to discuss you .
An imbalance in your fluids .
Strain to the major organs .
Depleted immune system .
Many indicators that you have in common
with most of my patients ...
but I will confess I have never seen a case ...
as advanced as this ...
in someone so young .
Is that right ?
( SIGHS )
Tell me , Mr. Lockhart ...
when was the last time that you actually felt well ?
Before you came here , when was the last time ...
that you even slept through the night ?
The mind may lie ...
but the body cannot .
I should like to help you .
What we offer here ...
is a simple process of purification .
Away from pressures of the modern world .
A return to a simpler time .
Mr. Pembroke will not be ready to travel for a day or two .
And if you 're willing ...
I would like to recommend a treatment .
I can speak to the duty nurse ...
and we may be able to start as early as this evening .
y . If you think it 's necessar
Good .
Greta ?
You 're in luck , Mr. Lockhart .
We can get you in right away .
LOCKHART : " VR . "
Von Reichmerl .
It was found during the reconstruction .
n ? Then it belong to the baro
The baroness , actually .
Vanessa Von Reichmerl .
She was sickly .
The Baron was obsessed with finding a cure .
It was he , in fact , who first discovered
the medicinal properties of our water .
. He sacrificed everything
He must have loved her very much .
Yes .
Like a sister .
History is right , of course , to judge him on moral grounds .
But , as a man of science ...
m . I can 't help but admire hi
The duty nurse will escort you to our isolation wing .
Thank you .
Mr. Lockhart ...
If you wouldn 't mind .
Just so we can keep an eye on your progress .
( TOILET FLUSHING )
( LID CLOSING )
Are you ready , Mr. Lockhart ?
( SPEAKS GERMAN )
Then let us begin .
Life on this planet first came from water .
We spend the first nine months of our existence submerged ...
our bodies mostly liquid .
This sensory deprivation chamber
simulates a return ...
to that embryonic state .
Think of it as a cleansing of the mind ...
as much as the body .
Some patients experience increased heart rate ...
visions ...
even primal memories .
But rest assured ,
it 's just the toxins leaving the system .
Give yourself over completely to the process ...
and you will see the results .
Keep a close eye on him .
. Yes , sir
. Mr. Lockhart ..
the treatment lasts 30 minutes .
I 'll be monitoring you from here .
. If you have any issues ..
just tap on the side of the tank .
( BOY LAUGHING )
Get back !
( LAUGHING )
( TECHNICIAN MASTURBATING )
( MUFFLED SHOUTING )
( CONTINUES SCREAMING )
( FLATLINING )
REPORTER : ( ON RADIO ) In the last five days ,
a total collapse .
The Dow plunging over 508 points ...
as panic spread throughout Wall Street ...
wiping out more than
one-third of the gains ... ( HORNS HONKING )
from this rare , five-year bull market .
More than half of that in a single trading day .
Chairman of New York Stock Exchange , John Phelan ...
tried to reassure investors .
Dad ?
Dad !
( COUGH
Mr. Lockhart , are you all right ?
Get off me .
NURSE : Try to stay calm .
TECHNICIAN : I 'm terribly sorry .
Something must have gone wrong with the machine .
There 's something in the water .
( LOCKHART COUGHS )
There 's something in the fucking water .
( COUGHING CONTINUES )
( PANTING )
There is nothing in the water , Mr. Lockhart .
But I saw them .
As the Director explained ...
some patients experience visions
with this particular treatment .
Just the toxins leaving the body .
It 's all part of the cure .
. TECHNICIAN : You need to rest now
I will help you to your room .
( LOCKHART GRUNTS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( NURSE SPEAKING GERMAN IN HALLWAY )
( VOICE FADES )
( RATTLING )
( RATTLING STOPS )
( TOILET HANDLE RATTLING )
NAIR : Got you .
HILL : Morning , Lockhart .
Feeling better ?
? Joining us for breakfast
The kedgeree is excellent .
I 'm not hungry .
You must keep up your strength .
LOCKHART : Mrs. Watkins ?
That building where the church used to be ...
What 's it used for now ?
I couldn 't say .
You were right about the baron and his sister .
But that 's not the reason
the villagers burned the place down .
It was on account of the experiments .
Some sort of medical experiments .
Apparently performed on his own peasants .
g . People went missing
.
Im Jahre 1814 ...
farmers , tilling their fields , stumbled on human bodies ...
disfigured and emaciated .
Dried up like the mummies of Egypt .
He was looking for a cure .
. A cure ? For the baroness
She was sick .
Oh , I see .
. I knew you liked puzzles
Of course .
ATTENDANT : Mrs. Watkins ...
time for your treatment .
Are you certain ?
I just had one this mornin g . I 'm sure of it .
I have you on the schedule .
I must not be feeling myself today .
There is a terrible darkness here .
What is this place ?
) ( SPEAKING GERMAN
I 'm sorry . I don 't understand .
I thought I saw you with a patient .
( SPEAKS GERMAN )
No . Patient .
Okay .
Thank you .
Going for a swim ?
I 'm not supposed to .
Why 's that ?
On the account of my condition .
Thought the water made you better .
. Told you . I 'm a special case
Right .
How far is it to town ?
A few miles , I think .
Are you going to walk all the way ?
Unless you wanna lend me your bike .
What will you give me ?
It was my mother 's .
d . Her eyes are close
. Yeah , she 's dreaming . She just doesn 't know it
? What happens if she wakes up
I don 't know .
My mother never finished the story .
So , we got a deal ?
? How will you ride it
Maybe you could come along .
o . I 'm not supposed t
You always do what you 're supposed to do ?
It 's okay .
Coming ?
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
( ROCK MUSIC PLAYING )
Want a beer or something ?
I don 't know . Do I ?
I don 't know what you want .
. All right . If you 're having one
ENRICO : Still here ?
Thought you were just visiting .
You 've looked better .
u . Same to yo
How 's the car ?
. That car was a piece of shit
Sanitarium offered me enou gh to buy a new one .
So , gracias a Dios .
t ? Everything happens for a reason , righ
You drink too much .
I hope you 're not driving .
You two are from up on the hill ?
That 's right .
e . We don 't get many patients down her
( LOUD CHATTERING )
( SHOUTS )
( SPEAKING GERMAN )
Good kids at heart .
. Just weren 't raised properly
. No respect for tradition
Know if there 's a doctor in town ?
All the doctors are up on the hill .
A pharmacist ?
t ? Something like tha
There 's Pieter . Over the road .
LOCKHART : He a doctor ?
Close enough .
( SOFT ROCK MUSIC PLAYING )
Don 't you like it ?
No .
What , you never had a beer before ?
How long have you been at the sanitarium ?
Since I can remember .
What about your family ?
My mother died in a fire when I was young .
Director Volmer says that my father will come for me
when I 'm better .
Does he visit ?
He 'll come when I 'm better .
Vitamins ? Mmm-hmm .
Can I try ?
HANNAH : Um ...
Okay .
Ugh .
( LAUGHING )
Tastes like sweaty seafood .
You get used to it . Eventually .
Will you be okay her e for a few minutes ?
I just have to go se e about something .
g . But I won 't be lon
Uh ... Yeah . Okay .
( VIDEO GAME PLAYING ON TV )
o ? LOCKHART : Hell
? Do you know if there 's a doctor here
What 's that you 're drawing ?
MAN : He won 't talk to you .
Doesn 't know how .
LOCKHART : That 's the castle ...
. when they burned it down
My grandson , Wilmosh .
He likes ghost stories .
What can I do for you ?
Could you take a look at this , tell me what it says ?
Human ?
. That 's right
Not my line .
I 'll pay you .
? How much is this
Not much .
But enough .
( HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING )
( WOMEN SPEAKING GERMAN )
Got a tampon ?
My friend 's time of the month .
Freak .
So is he fit to travel ?
n . He 's not a well ma
Some of those are dental records , aren 't they ?
That 's right . What do they mean ?
His teeth are falling out .
What could cause something like that ?
Barring any pre-existi ng condition , I 'd say ...
n . chronic dehydratio
Dehydration ?
All they do up there is drink water .
. I 'm not a doctor
Now , if you 'll excuse me ...
Wait a second .
The baron 's experiments .
They found bodies in the fields , right ?
Dried up like mummies .
Maybe there 's some kind of connection .
The baron was burned alive
on his wedding nig ht 200 years ago .
Yeah , but this is happening now .
People come here for the cure .
That 's what the baron was looking for .
His wife was sick .
k . She wasn 't sic
She was infertile .
PIETER : They tried for years .
But the baroness could not carry a child to term .
es They say her body rejected the fetus
because they were deformed .
e . Now , you must excuse m
I have to put this animal out of its misery .
What 's wrong with it ?
Wandered off where it wasn 't supposed to be .
Broke its leg .
Like you .
Found it trapped in a drainage ditch ...
drinking sewage water .
( WHINES )
( FUNKY GERMAN MUSIC PLAYING )
I need to make a phone call . Long distance .
. Your credit card
GREEN : Lockhart .
Mr. Green .
? Where the hell have you been
. LOCKHART : I have a question
Did Pembroke have any pre-existing conditions ?
What are you talking about ?
Before he got here .
Any medical conditions ? Was he sick ?
. No . The guy is a fucking health nut
. Drank kale for Christ 's sake
Now what the fuck is going on ?
You were supposed to be here four days ago .
Yeah . But there was an accident .
What accident ?
What ?
I don 't understand . They said they called you .
Nobody called .
Are you sure about that ?
Lockhart , do I have to reiterate to you ...
the importance of what you 've been sent there to do ?
. Get Pembroke on a plane within the next 24 hours ..
or this whole place goes ass over tits .
And you with it . Understand me ?
Lockhart ?
Lockhart !
I need to speak with you Hey , hey , hey .
You said no one ever leaves . What does that mean ?
You 're hurting me .
. What happens to them ? Please let me go
Why won 't they let me see Pembroke ?
You know something , don 't you ?
No .
What is this stuff ? What makes you special ?
( SPEAKING GERMAN ) Fuck off , Adolf !
BARTENDER : Hey !
Come on . No !
I paid for this dance . No !
Let her go !
Go back to the sanitarium , cripple .
No !
! No ! Please , stop
I am not a patient .
( SPEAKING GERMAN )
( VOLMER SHOUTS IN GERMAN )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( CHAIR CLATTERING )
Hannah .
LOCKHART : Hannah .
She may look like a woman ...
but she 's just a child .
Ignorance , Mr. Lockhart ...
is the great enemy of science .
. I wanna see Pembroke
And you will .
( ENGINE STARTS )
? Coming , Mr. Lockhart
HANNAH : Nothing happened .
VOLMER : That 's because I arrived when I did .
. Lockhart was there
With a knife to his throat .
Hannah ...
Mr. Lockhart is not able to look after himself ,
let alone you .
He can 't protect you the way I can .
I don 't need protecting .
Of course you do .
n . We were just having fu
. He 's not like the others
He 's young .
( HANNAH GROANS )
What ?
g . What is it ? HANNAH : Nothin
Let me see . No .
I 'm your doctor . Come here .
No ! Don 't touch me !
( SIGHS )
When will I be ready ?
Soon .
When ?
. Patience
Come here .
I said , come here .
Now , haven 't I alway s looked after you ?
. Soon , I will make you better
And you will thank me .
And my father will come ?
Yes .
Get some rest , my little lamb .
( CREAKING )
( GASPS )
( PANTING )
( TOILET HANDLE RATTLING )
Bitte ?
I have a problem with my ...
May I ?
I 'll just pop it in some milk , shall I ?
There we are .
( NURSE SPEAKING GERMAN )
( BELL DINGS )
( SCREAMS )
( SPEAKING GERMAN )
( CONTINUES SCREAMING )
) ( SPEAKING GERMAN
( GASPS )
( CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING )
( PEOPLE CHATTERING IN GERMAN )
Mrs. Watkins ?
Where 's Pembroke ?
You took him .
Back to New York .
What ? No .
They moved him . He 's down here somewhere .
You told me about the experiments , remember ?
Your puzzle ?
I like puzzles .
Yeah .
I left it for you .
You 'll see .
Listen to me .
The experiments ...
I think they 're happening again .
The baroness was infertile .
Not experiments .
A cure .
. She was pregnant the night of the wedding
. Before they burned her ..
the villagers cut ou t the fetus ...
r . and threw it in the aquife
The child survived .
She doesn 't know .
( PANTING )
( GRUNTING )
( SPEAKING GERMAN )
I 'm sorry , I don 't understand .
Take it easy .
Marcus !
. It 's all right
Mr. Lockhart ...
every time I turn around ,
you 're somewhere you 're not supposed to be .
. I guess I 'm lost
I 'm just trying to find my way back to my room .
( SCOFFS ) This is a restricted floor .
There are signs everywhere .
Surely you didn 't just wande r down here by accident ?
What is it exactly that you are looking for ?
I had a problem with my tooth .
Your tooth ?
. Actually , it 's feeling much better
m . If you could just point me in the direction of my roo
Nonsense .
We can 't let you get an infection .
You must let us take care of you .
After all ...
's why you 're here . at
Doctor Brennan takes care
of all our patients dental needs .
( BRENNAN AND VOLMER CONVERSING IN GERMAN )
I 'm sorry .
Hmm ?
About Hannah .
It won 't happen again .
Hmm .
Tell me ...
n ? what were you doing in tow
Just having a beer . ( CHUCKLES )
m . Ah . Hm
What are you doing ?
Get your hands off me !
It 's all for your own safety , Mr. Lockhart .
e . We don 't believe in chemic al anesthesia at the institut
. The impurities inhibit the cure
But , you will find that with a proper focus ...
the mind can overcom e any amount of pain .
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
? Trust , Mr. Lockhart . Hmm
I mean , if we can 't trust each other ...
u ? then how can I help yo
( MACHINE WHIRRING )
( LOCKHART SCREAMING )
DEPUTY DIRECTOR : Mrs. Abramov ...
so glad that you are here .
? How long do we have you with us
Just two weeks .
I probably overpacked .
Nonsense .
You 'll be surprised how time just slips away
here at the institute .
( EXCLAIMS IN GERMAN )
Drive !
What happened to your face ?
Just drive !
( GRUNTING )
They held me down and pulled my tooth out .
They threatened me .
Why would they do that ?
Because I know what they 've done .
There is a room full of bodies
floating in tanks like specimens .
. These are very serious allegations
No shit .
Director Volmer is a well-respected man .
The sanatorium is of great importance
for the local economy .
Take me up there , and I 'll show you what I saw .
Do you have any identification on you ?
No , they have everything .
Well , then , is there someo ne I could speak to ...
y ? who might confirm you are who you say you are ? Famil
I hope you understand the need to verify your identity .
You can call my office .
All right .
a ? Can I get you coffee or te
You got anything stronger ?
Of course .
Rest assured ...
we will get to the bottom of this .
Thank you .
( SIGHS )
( CHUCKLES )
Mr. Lockhart , we 've been worried about you .
Stay away from me !
Is this man a patient of yours ?
Yes , that 's right .
. I 'm not a patient . I was in an accident
You signed the admission form . I have it right here .
That 's bullshit .
I did warn you about possible delusions , remember ?
A side effect of the toxins leaving the body .
? And my leg , is that a delusion
Mr. Lockhart has been a disruptive element
since he arrived .
He stole confidential medical files ...
assaulted a member of our Dental staff ...
and threatened Mr. Pembroke .
I didn 't threaten anybody !
I believe your exact words were ...
" If I have to , I 'll hit him over the head
" and drag him out by his hair . "
I was sent here to bring Pembroke back to New York !
According to your employer , a Mr. Green ...
you 're being investigated
by the Securities and Exchange Commission .
You 're one of them .
VOLMER : Listen to yourself , Mr. Lockhart .
You 're not a well man .
Stop saying that !
Let us help you . Get back !
. I know about the experiments
The baron and his wife .
He has been spending time with Mrs. Watkins .
CONSTABLE : Who is Watkins ?
She was institutionalized before she came to us .
The others humor her ...
but clearly Mr. Lockhart 's condition
has made him susceptib le to her conspiracies .
. I know what you 're trying to do . All of you
You 're trying to make me think I 'm insane .
I have seen this before .
It 's not uncommon .
Some deep-seated childhood trauma rises to the surface ...
something a patient has been running from
their entire life .
In your case ...
I would say misplaced guilt ...
over the death of your father .
How do you know about that ? I never told you that .
You didn 't have to .
That 's why you came to us , isn 't it ?
I saw him .
. Pembroke is dead
( SCOFFS ) That 's what this is all about ?
The evil doctor killing off his patients ?
That 's right .
All right . Perhaps we shou ld consult Mr. Pembroke .
? Do you know this man
He tried to take me back against my will .
Pembroke ?
Please keep him away from me .
You were dead .
CONSTABLE : Do you wish press charges ?
VOLMER : That won 't be necessary .
Mr. Lockhart is not a criminal .
He is a patient .
( TOILET HANDLE RATTLING )
( GASPING )
( GRUNTING )
LOCKHART : To the members of the board ...
You sent me here for a purpose .
To retrieve a man against his will ...
and bring him back to your world .
But I realize now ...
that is not the reason I am here .
There is a sickness inside each of us .
We do our best to deny its existence ...
dealing in lies ...
and distraction .
Until one day the body rebels against the mind
and screams out ...
" I am not a well man . "
A man cannot unsee the truth .
He cannot willingly return to darkness ...
or go blind once he has the gift of sight ...
any more than he can be unborn .
( MACHINE WHIRRING )
( FAINT WHIRRING )
( GROANING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
Fuck .
( YELLS )
( SCREAMING )
( PANTING )
( CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING )
Hannah !
( MAN SHOUTING IN GERMAN )
Stay away from me .
Hannah . Stay away from me .
We need to go . I said stay away !
( LOCKHART GROANS )
There . Everything is all right .
Please enjoy your meal .
Hannah ?
What have you done ?
? What 's happening to me
. Here , here , here
w . It 's all right . You 're safe no
Leave her alone .
Haven 't you upset her enough , Mr. Lockhart ?
Please , escort the patient back to his room .
I am not a fucking patient !
( PATIENTS GASP )
Come on !
Had enough of cripples and old people ?
Try it with me !
That 's enough ! Mr. Lockhart ...
I can see you 're extremely upset .
Why don 't you come with me to my office ...
and we can discuss whatever 's on your mind .
No .
We 're gonna talk about it right here .
In front of everybody .
I don 't think that 's a good idea .
. He 's making you sick
This place is making you sick !
( PATIENTS GASPING )
It 's in the water .
Mr. Lockhart .
I saw the bodies dried up like mummies !
Look at you people !
Your teeth are falling out !
You 're dying , and you can 't even see it .
But I 'm here for the cure .
There is no cure !
G ) ( PATIENTS MURMURIN
Don 't you see ?
He 's the one that is making you sick !
There 's nothing wron g with you people !
I wouldn 't do that , if I were you .
There 's nothing wron g with you .
Yes .
Yes !
That 's it !
Stand up !
Come on !
Yes !
Stand up !
He is making you sick !
Yes , that 's it . Come on .
That 's it !
There 's nothing wrong with you !
I am not well .
PATIENTS : I am not well .
What are you doing ?
( ALL REPEATING )
Get the fuck off me !
No . No , no !
Get off me .
Help me ! Help !
( SCREAMING )
( CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING )
Pembroke .
What have they done to you ?
Done to me ?
I 've never felt better .
Relax , Mr. Lockhart .
It 'll all be over soon .
Ah , yes . Remarkable creatures .
Anywhere else on the planet ,
this species lives a dozen years , at most .
Here , in our aquifer ...
they can live 300 .
For the human physiology ...
the effect of the water can be quite toxic
as you have discovered .
Unless , of course , it is properly filtered .
The baron devised the process .
Using the bodies of peasants that belonged to his land ...
he managed to distill the water ...
to its life-giving essence .
Of course , he paid
a terrible price for his ingenuity .
His only mistake ...
was to use subjects who were unwilling .
Luckily , times have changed .
The last 200 years
y . have been the most productive in human histor
Man rid himself of God ...
of hierarchy , of everything that gave him meaning ...
until he was left worshiping
the empty altar of his own ambition .
( GASPS )
( PANICKED GRUNTING )
That is why they come .
Men like you .
You 're quite right , Mr. Lockhart .
No one ever leaves .
What you fail to understand is that no one wants to .
( MUFFLED GROANING )
Do you know what the cure for the human condition is ?
Disease .
Because only then is there hope for a cure .
( WHIMPERING )
I don 't understand .
.. For so many years , I 've tried to protect you .
. from the impurities of the outside world
rt But ironically , it is your friend Mr. Lockha
. who we have to thank
You 're a woman now .
But I 'm not well .
And I will always be here to take care of you .
HANNAH : She 's awake now .
You made me believe I could leave here one day .
Why would anybody wanna leave ?
What is it ?
Come .
What is this place ?
This is where you began .
I don 't want to .
( SHUSHING )
You know ...
you look just like she did on her wedding night .
The night they took her from me .
WATKINS : The villagers cut out the fetus
and threw it in the aquifer .
The child survived .
( OBJECTS CLATTERING )
Please don 't .
d . Don 't be frightene
. Soon we 'll be a family again
The way we were always meant to be .
( HANNAH GRUNTING )
( HANNAH PANTING )
VOLMER : ( SHUSHING ) It 's all right .
My sister was also somewhat resistant , at first .
But after a while , she grew to like it .
We tried so many times to make something pure .
That something was you , my love .
And now ...
we can begin again .
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( SHUSHING )
( HANNAH WHIMPERING )
( SNIFFS )
g . I 've waited so lon
So long .
He will have you . Yes ?
Yes . ( CONTINUES WHIMPERING )
You can 't keep her here forever .
No ?
And what do you think would become of her in your world ?
People like you come to me in droves
with your disposable lives .
r . She 's your daughte
And what have you ever loved , hmm ?
What have you ever sacrificed ?
This is what the outside world has to offer .
( SCREAMS ) ( GROANS )
You 're right .
No .
( GASPS ) ( VOLMER GROANING )
( SCREAMING )
( CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING )
( GRUNTING )
( GASPS )
( GROANS )
No .
( GRUNTING )
Fire . Fire !
( PEOPLE SCREAMING )
( SCREAMS )
( COUGHING )
( SCREAMING CONTIN
( CHOKING )
Everything I have built has been for her .
You think I would let someone like you destroy that ?
HANNAH : Dad ?
Hannah .
( VOLMER GROANS )
( ALL SCREAMING )
( BOTH COUGHING )
Magnificent , isn 't it ?
Lockhart !
It 's time to go .
( HANNAH SCREAMS )
( GROANS )
Are you okay ? Jesus Christ .
Easy , easy .
Lockhart ?
WILSON : My God .
What have you done ?
Where 's Pembroke ?
He 's gone .
What do you mean " gone " ?
Get in the car .
You came here to perform a task , remember ?
Now get in the car .
Did you hear what I said ?
d ? Have you lost your min
Actually ...
I 'm feeling much better .
Where the hell are you going ?
Lockhart ! Lockhart !
( HANNAH SINGING MELANCHOLY TUNE )